지난 이야기
닐
Neal.
아버지가 도망가고
엘렌이 절 돌봐줬죠
When my dad went away,
Ellen looked after me.
샘이요? 아버질
아는 사람이에요?
Sam?
Did he know my father?
연락하기 어려운 사람이야
A hard guy to get hold of.
누구 짓이에요?
Who did this to you?
샘을 믿거라
Trust Sam.
샘을 찾을 어떤
정보라도 얻게 되면..
If you find any information
that leads to Sam...
말씀 드릴게요
I will tell you.
중간 지점에서 만나자고 해
You tell him you want to meet
on neutral ground.
"원하시는 방법으로 만나요"
차에 타게
Get in the car.
답장을 주실지 몰랐어요, 샘
I wasn't sure
I'd hear back from you, Sam.
어디로 가나요?
Where are we going?
눈에 덜 띄는 곳
Someplace less obvious.
카프리나 베넷 뭘로
불러야 하나?
So do I call you Caffrey
or Bennett?
베넷은 오래 전
제 이름이었죠
Bennett was my name
a long time ago.
이젠 아니에요
Not anymore.
자넬 추적해 왔네, 지난 번..
I've been tracking you
since --
엘렌의 장례식 부터요
Ellen's funeral.
기억해요
I remember.
난 캐서린 힐이란
이름으로 알았지
I knew her as Kathryn Hill.
증인 보호 전
엘렌의 이름이요?
Ellen's name before WITSEC?
D.C에서 꽤 깊이
위장 수사를 하셨다구요
She told me you worked
deep cover back in D.C.,
꽤 근접했다고 하시던데요
said you were close.
네 아버지가
살인 혐의를 쓰고
After your father
went down for murder,
우리 부서엔 믿을
사람이 별로 없었어
there weren't many
in our department I could trust.
아버질 아셨어요?
You knew my dad?
이메일에 내 방식대로
만나자고 했지
In your e-mail, you said
you'd meet me on my terms.
내 방식은 이거야
내가 질문을 하고
Here are my terms.
I ask the questions.
답이 맘에 들지 않으면
차에 타고 떠날 거야
I don't like the answers,
I get back in that car,
and I drive away.
이해했나?
Understood?
네
Understood.
FBI에서 뭐하는 건가?
What do you do for the FBI?
자문이에요
I'm a confidential informant.
감옥에서 나오는
조건이었어요
It's the deal I cut
to get out of prison.
장례식의 그 남자가
핸들러인가?
The man at the funeral --
your handler?
피터 버크요
믿을 수 있는 분이에요
Peter Burke.
He can be trusted.
저희를 도와서
엘렌의..
He can help us find
Ellen's --
이게 단순 살인
사건이라고 생각한다면
If you think this is about
one guy pulling one trigger,
네 아버지처럼
순진한 거다
you're as naive as your father.
네 아비를 끌어내리고
엘렌을 죽인 자들..
The men who took him down --
the men who had Ellen murdered.
부패 경찰이었죠
They were corrupt cops.
이젠 높은 자리에
한 자리씩 꿰찼지
Who rose up the ranks of
government and law enforcement.
분명 FBI안에도 있을 거야
I'm sure there are some
in the bureau.
자기들을 보호하려고
무슨 짓이든 할 거고
And they will do whatever it
takes to protect themselves.
그래서 엘렌이 절 도와
폭로하라고 하셨어요?
So, what? She asked you
to help me expose them?
FBI랑 일하는 건
조건이 아니었어
Working with the FBI
wasn't part of the deal.
요원님이 도와주실 수 있어요
Peter can help us.
한장의 보고서 때문이었어
All it takes is one report.
어떻게 엘렌의 이름이
새나간 것 같나?
How do you think
Ellen's name got leaked?
아뇨, 요원님은 아니에요
No. Not Peter.
좋아요, 둘이서
해결한다면
All right, assuming
this stays between us,
놈들을 어떻게 잡죠?
how do we take them down?
엘렌이 30년 전 모은
부패 경찰 자료에서 시작해야지
Start with the evidence
Ellen collected on dirty cops
30 years ago.
어디 있나?
Where is it?
여기 오셨을 때
주실 계획이었어요
She was planning to hand
that over when she got here.
어디 있는지
모른다는 건가?
So you don't even know
where it is?
- 기회를 주세요
- 미안하네, 카프리
Give me a chance.
Sorry, Caffrey.
이미 마음에 안 드는
대답이 도를 넘었어
You've already maxed out on your
quota of answers I don't like.
이게 끝이에요?
그냥 가신다고요?
So that's it?
You're leaving?
샘, 엘렌과 아버지에
대한 진실을 알고 싶어요
Sam, I need the truth
about Ellen and my father.
네 아버지를
알았냐고 물었지
You asked me if I knew him.
알았네
I did.
열쇠가 구멍 안에서
부러졌다고?
- So, the key broke off in the lock?
- Yeah.
응
렌탈인게 확실해?
Are you sure it's a rental?
새 모델에 짧은 주행거리
싸구려 플라스틱 장식품
New model, low mileage,
cheap plastic key fob.
육각형이군
Hexagonal.
스트릿 플릿 아니면
제니스일 거야
That's either street fleet
or zenith.
열쇠 구멍이 막혀서
수리가 필요한
I'll keep an eye out
for repair requests
회색 SUV가 있는지
잘 살펴볼게
on a gray S.U.V. with a key
stuck in the door lock.
좋아
All right.
샘을 다시 찾는다고 쳐보자
Let's say you find Sam --
again.
널 믿지 않았잖아
He's made it clear
he doesn't trust you.
믿어도 된다고
설득해야지
Well, I have to convince him
that he can.
신뢰란 쌍방으로
이루어지는 거야
You know,
trust works both ways.
내가 샘을 믿지
않는다고?
You don't think
I should trust Sam?
내 말은 양쪽 눈을
크게 뜨고 보란 거야
I'm simply saying you should
go in with both eyes open.
그리고 아저씨한테
그 눈이 될 자원들이 있다고
And the Suit has the resources
to be those eyes.
오늘 혹시 해가
서쪽에서 떴어?
You realize somewhere
pigs are flying right now.
그래, 지옥이
얼어붙을 소리지
Yes. And that is the sound
of hell freezing over.
네가 무슨 일 벌이는
낌새를 채면
Look, Peter catches wind
you're up to something,
널 미행하실 거야
he's gonna follow you.
먼저 알려드리는 게
나을 거라고
He may as well be informed.
그리고 공식적으로
조사를 하시면
Yeah, and if he puts
his investigation on the books,
요원님이 위험해져
it could put him at risk.
비공식으로 해달라고 해
전에도 했잖아
You could ask him to be quiet.
He's done it before.
내켜하진 않으셨지
Yeah, well, not happily.
그래도 하셨잖아
But he's done it.
11월 6일 콘도 개발
투자자로 가장하여
On November 6th, you visited
the defendant's penthouse,
posing as an investor
for his condo development.
피고의 펜트하우스를
방문하셨죠
어떤 증거를 발견하셨나요?
What evidence did you uncover?
딜랜시가 병에 든
벤젠을 보여줬습니다
Delancy showed me
a vial of benzene.
암의 원인으로
알려졌다면서요
He said it was known
to cause cancer,
특히 백혈병이요
specifically leukemia.
그 벤젠으로 어떤 일을
할 계획인지 말 했나요?
Did he say what he planned to do
with this particular vial?
캐플린사가 조사하는
토양 샘플에
He said he planned to use it
to lace the soil samples
taken by Caplin Environmental.
소량 섞을
계획이라고 했습니다
독성이 있다는
결과가 나오면
When the results
would come back toxic,
자기 소유의 땅에서
임차인을 쫓아내고
he'd evict the tenants
from his property,
집을 허물어
tear down their homes,
자신의 고급 콘도를
지을 계획이라고요
and eventually
start construction
on his luxury condos,
전과 똑같은 수법으로요
exactly as he'd done
once before.
딜랜시가 이 병을
보여 준 후..
After Delancy showed you
this vial...
딜랜시 재판을 준비하시는 건가요?
Peter working on his direct
for the Delancy trial?
검사측의 주요
증인이잖아요
Ah, he's the prosecution's
star witness.
범죄자 체포보다
좋아하시는 유일한 게..
And the only thing he loves more
than arresting criminals...
재판에서 범인들
상대로 증언하는 거죠
Is testifying against them
at their trial.
기억나요, 생생하게
Oh, I remember.
Vividly.
완벽해요, 제가 질문을 끝내고
Perfect. Then I say,
"no further questions,"
모두 잘 풀린다면..
and if all goes well...
딜랜시가 담보 사기와
98건의 인권침해에 대해
The jury finds Delancy guilty
of mortgage fraud
and 98 counts
of civil rights violations.
유죄라는 걸
배심원도 알게 되겠죠
FBI가 벤젠 병을
회수하지 못 했으니
And since the FBI never
recovered the benzene vial,
이 사건은 요원님
증언에 달렸어요
this whole case is resting
on your testimony.
검사님의 핵심 질문도요
And your key question.
크리스마스 아침 유죄 판결을
선물 받는 기분이겠네요
It's like
it's Christmas morning
and he's unwrapping
a guilty verdict.
소량 섞었다고
말하는 대신
Oh. Instead of "laced,"
샘플이 오염됐다고
말할게요
I'll say the samples
were "tainted."
오염됐다는 게
좀 더 서술적이잖아요
Tainted's more descriptive.
닐, 조쉬 브라이슨 기억하지
Neal, you remember Josh Bryson,
- 연방 검사
- 검사님
assistant U.S. attorney.
Josh.
딜랜시의 변호를
뭉개버리셨다면서요
I hear you've been wiping the
floor with the Delancy defense.
오늘 요원님의
증언까지 더해서
And with
Peter's testimony today,
그 비참함에서
구해줄 생각입니다
I plan to put them
out of their misery.
저도 요원님과 함께
일했단 거 잊지 마세요
Don't forget
I worked that case with Peter.
딜랜시가 저한테도
벤젠을 보여줬죠
Delancy showed me the vial
of benzene, too,
캐플린사의 생화학 분석가로
위장했을때요, 그러니까..
when I was working undercover
at Caplin Environmental
as a biochemical analyst,
so if you --
고맙지만 이미
요원님이 있고..
Thank you, Neal,
but I already have Peter.
요원님은..
And he, uh...
어떻게 말해야 하죠?
How do I put this?
어둡고 야비한 프로
사기꾼의 과거가 없다고요?
Doesn't have a dark and sordid
past as a professional con man?
진실하고 사이가
나쁘지도 않다구요?
Or an off-again, off-again
relationship with the whole truth?
- 또..
- 알아들었거든요
Or even --
Point taken, so...
방청석에서 증언하는 거
구경해도 돼
You're more than welcome
to sit in the gallery
and watch me testify.
그러고 싶지만, 전..
Ah, I would love to,
but I should --
그냥 여기서
연필이나 깎아야겠어요
you know, I should probably stay
here and just sharpen pencils.
- 한 시간 후에 보죠
- 알았어요
I'll see you in an hour, Peter.
All right, Josh.
재판 잘 하세요
Have a great trial.
고마워요
Thank you.
언제부터 그렇게
증언에 관심있었어?
Since when are you interested
in taking the stand?
증언이 사기란 걸
깨닫고 부터요
Ever since I realized
that testifying is a con.
사기 아니야
Testifying isn't a con.
배심원에게 큰
영향을 줄 수 있도록
It's a narrative
crafted to have
the greatest impact on a jury.
잘 짜여진 이야기지
그 이야기가 옳다고
납득시키는 거니
You're convincing the jury
your narrative is right.
사기죠
It's a con.
아냐, 사기엔
거짓말이 들어가지
Nope.
Conning involves deceit.
의도된 생략은
거짓말이 아니라고요?
Oh, a lie of omission
is not deceit?
내 증언에 의도된
생략은 없어
My testimony
isn't a lie of omission.
나중에 영장을 가지고 갔을 때
Are you mentioning the part
where the benzene
was nowhere to be found
벤젠을 찾을 수 없었던
부분은 어때요?
when you showed up
with the warrant later?
뭘 회수했는지가 아니라
뭘 알아냈는지 물을 거야
Bryson is asking what
I uncovered, not recovered.
큰 차이지
Big difference.
그럼 대답만큼
질문도 중요하다는 거죠
So, testifying is as much
about the questions
as it is the answers.
맞아
Exactly.
그럼 정정할게요
Then I stand corrected.
증언은 2인조 사기예요
Testifying
is a two-man con.
가서 연필이나 깎아
Go sharpen your pencils.
알았어요
Okay.
그래서 집을 허물고
...which allowed him
to tear down their homes
고급 콘도를
지을 수 있게요
to build luxury condos.
그리고 버크씨가 이 계획을
다시 시도한다고 의심하셨군요
And you suspected Mr. Burke
would attempt this scheme
a second time?
딜랜시씨 말씀이죠
You mean Mr. Delancy.
정정하겠습니다
I will restate.
딜랜시씨가 이 계획을 다시
시도한다고 의심하셨군요
You suspected Mr. Delancy
would attempt the scheme
a second time.
Correct.
그렇습니다
딜랜시는 또다른 콘도 개발
투자자를 찾고 있었습니다
He was looking for an investor
for another condo development.
제가 그 투자자로 위장했죠
While undercover,
I was that investor.
기소 배심 증언때
Now, in your grand jury
testimony,
작년 11월 6일 피고인의
펜트하우스를 방문했다고 진술했죠
you state that you visited
the defendant's penthouse
on November 6th of last year.
그 날
On that date,
지난 범죄에 대한
어떤 증거를 회수했나요?
what evidence of his previous
crime did you recover?
발견했냐는 말씀이죠
You mean uncover?
맞습니다, 그 날
Correct. On that date,
지난 범죄에 대한
어떤 증거를 회수했나요?
what evidence of Delancy's
previous crime did you recover?
그날, 회수한 증거는 없습니다
That date,
I didn't recover any evidence,
하지만 피고가
제게 보여준..
but the defendant
showed me --
이의 있습니다
관련 없는 답입니다
Objection.
Non-responsive.
인정합니다
Sustained.
정정하죠
I-I will restate.
버크 요원, 그 날
어떤 증거를 발견했습니까?
Agent Burke, on that date,
what evidence did you uncover?
딜랜시가 제게
벤젠 병을 보여줬습니다
Mr. Delancy showed me
a vial of benzene.
요원님
Hey.
닐
점심 먹으러 가다
어떻게 됐나 들렀어요
Thought I'd swing by
on my lunch, see how it went.
보아하니 잘 안풀렸나봐요
By the looks of it, not well.
브라이슨이 망쳐놨어
Bryson blew it.
긴장해서
안절부절 못 했어
He was nervous, jumpy.
핵심 질문도 망쳤다고
He botched the key question.
브라이슨은 그런
실수 안 하는데요
Bryson doesn't botch anything.
맞아
Exactly.
브라이슨이 딜랜시한테
넘어갔을까요?
Peter, you don't think Delancy
might have gotten to him.
사실이라면 범죄자가
풀려나게 될 거야
If he did,
a guilty man is gonna walk.
4x7 Compromising Positions
한글번역 DC 기미갤 Ysfinn
조쉬, 들어와요
Hey, Josh. Come on in.
커피라도 줄까요?
Can I get you something?
Coffee?
감사합니다, 사모님
Thanks, Elizabeth.
어서와요
Glad you came.
대체 무슨 일이에요?
Josh, what the hell happened?
오늘 재판 전에
전화를 받았어요
Before court today,
I received a phone call.
사건을 망치지 않으면
이걸 공개하겠다고요
I was told to throw the case
or these go public.
조쉬
Josh.
Wow.
포토샵 한 사진은
아닌 거군요?
I take it
these aren't photoshopped?
사진 속 여자
오늘 법정에 있었어요
The woman in these photos --
she was in the court today.
딜랜시의 여자친구예요
She's Delancy's girlfriend.
피고의 여자친구랑 자다니
Sleeping with
the defense's girlfriend.
무효심리의 근거가
될 수도 있어요
This is grounds for a mistrial.
- 조쉬..
- 생각하시는 거랑은 달라요
Josh --
It's not what you think.
몇 주 전에 퇴근 후
한 잔 하러 바에 갔어요
A few weeks back, I'm in a bar,
grabbing a drink after work.
매력적인 여자가
작업을 걸어왔죠
This attractive woman approaches
and starts chatting me up.
자기 집으로 초대하더라고요
She invites me
over to her place.
그 다음은 아시겠죠
You get the idea.
지금 보고 있네요
Oh, no.
We see the idea.
오늘 아침까진
그 여자 정체를 몰랐어요
I swear to you,
before this morning,
I had no idea who she was.
오늘 일부러
망친 건가요?
Did you throw today on purpose?
아뇨
No.
당황에서
어쩔 줄을 몰랐어요
I got rattled.
I didn't know what to do.
당신이 물러나면
And if you step down,
범죄자가 풀려날
절호의 기회겠네요
there's a good chance
a criminal goes free.
이 나쁜 놈들을 잡아놓고
기소할 수 없다면 무슨 소용이야
What's the point
of arresting these bastards
if you can't prosecute them?
도와주실래요?
Can you help?
이 사진들이 브라이슨을
협박하는데 쓰였어
These are the photos
being used to blackmail Bryson.
딜랜시의 여자친구군요?
That's Delancy's girlfriend?
참 헌신적인 여자네요
She is dedicated
to her man.
유연하구요
And limber.
불행히도 여자는
입을 안 열어
And unfortunately,
she's not talking.
그럼 차선책을 쫓아야지
We'll have to go after
the next best thing.
랜던 쉐퍼드
Landon Shepard.
작년 딜랜시가 체포된 직 후
처음 전화 한 여자야
She was Delancy's first call
after his arrest last year.
어제 법정에도 있었고
And she was in court yesterday.
책임 고문이라고
되어있네요
Says she's
an executive consultant.
포츈 500대 기업의
CEO가 18살 먹은 정부랑
She's who you call
when the C.E.O.
of your Fortune 500 company
벤틀리 타고가다 사고냈을 때
전화하는 사람이지
crashes his Bentley
with his 18-year-old
mistress's head on his lap.
혹은 FBI가
수사망을 좁히는데
Or when the FBI is closing in
책상 서랍에 벤젠 병을
갖고 있을 때도요
and you've got a vial of benzene
in the top drawer of your desk.
- 해결사군요
- 실력이 좋아요, 연줄도 있고
- She's a fixer.
- She's good. She's connected.
일년이 지났는데도
아무 혐의점이 없죠
A year later, we still
can't pin anything on her.
전화 기록에
영장을 받을 수 없어요?
Can we subpoena
her phone records?
모든 수신 전화는
회사 음성 메일로 연결돼요
All incoming calls
go to an office voicemail.
지금까진 어떤
전화번호도 못 알아냈어
So far, we've been unable
to link any other number to her.
머릿속을 꿰뚫죠
She gets in your head.
작년에 5분 심문했는데
I mean, I questioned her a
year ago, and in five minutes,
나에 대해 우리 엄마보다
많이 알더라니까요
she could tell things about me
that my own mother couldn't.
그건 아니죠
It wasn't right.
연락할 방법을 찾아야 해
We have to find a way
to get to her.
아님 직접 올 수도 있고요
Or she could come to us.
다이애나
Diana.
쉐퍼드양, 제 이름은..
Ms. Shepard,
my name is --
버크 요원님
Agent Burke.
제 뒤를 캐고
다니신다고요
I hear you've been asking
questions about me
behind my back.
또다시요
Again.
들러서 수고를
덜어드리려고요
I thought I'd stop by
and save you the trouble.
배리건 요원과 전
기꺼이 대화하고 싶군요
Agent Berrigan and I
would love to chat with you.
클린턴 존스는 없나요?
No Clinton Jones today?
말하지 말아요
Don't tell me.
실적 좀 올려 아빠의
인정을 받으려 나갔군요
He's off seeking
daddy's approval
through overachievement.
15분 있어요
I got 15 minutes.
심문실은 이쪽이죠?
I assume your interrogation room
is this way.
딜랜시의 여자친구에
대해 뭘 알려주실 수 있나요?
What can you tell us about
Victor Delancy's girlfriend?
전 많은 사람들의
많은 면을 알죠
I can tell you a lot of things
about a lot of people.
구체적으로요
Specifics.
요원님이요, 믿음직한
남편에 존경받는 요원
Well, take you --
loyal husband, respected agent.
거의 완벽하세요
And you're
virtually untouchable.
하지만 딜랜시 사건
담당 검사는요?
But the assistant U.S. attorney
working the Delancy case --
완벽과는 거리가
멀다더군요
not so much from what I hear.
빅터 딜랜시가 고객이란 걸
인정하는겁니까
So you admit
Victor Delancy's a client?
제 고객들은 익명을
기대하니 아니죠
Oh, my clients expect
anonymity. I admit nothing.
저 여자한텐
게임이군요
It's a game to her.
내가 잘 몰랐더라면
If I didn't know any better,
내 존재를 감지했다고
생각했을 거예요
I'd think she senses
my presence.
책임 고문이라고
하시더군요
You call yourself
an executive consultant.
어떤 일을 하시나요?
What does that entail?
고객에게 필요한
정보를 제공하죠
I provide my clients
with much-needed structure.
내가 보는 걸
당신도 인정할 거예요
Something I see
you could appreciate.
- 무슨 말인지
- 문신이요
I'm not following.
Well, your tattoo.
사각형은 안정과
기반을 상징하죠
Squares symbolize stability,
foundation.
그 사이에 줄은
관계를 상징하고요
The line connecting them
signifies companionship.
아주 깊은 사랑에 빠졌군요
You must have been
very much in love.
옅어진 색으로 봐선
5년 전쯤요
Five years ago,
I'd say from the fading.
문신은 영원하죠
Tattoos are forever.
사랑은 그렇지 않지만요
Love, I guess not so much so.
- 이봐요
- 진정해
Listen, you --
Easy.
여자가 심문을
주도하고 있어요
She's controlling
the entire interview.
네, 요원님이
그렇게 만드니까요
Yeah, because
Peter's letting her.
쉐퍼드의 기를 살려주네요
He's playing to Shepard's ego.
- 왜요?
- 모르죠
Why?
I don't know.
소문에 의하면, 아주
높은 사람들을 안다고요
Rumor has it you know
some powerful people.
원하는 걸 갖기 위해
사람들에게 의지하죠
Well, I rely on the people
I know to get what I want,
시장님부터
창문닦이까지요
from the mayor to the man
who washes my windows.
일찍 만났으면
좋았을 뻔했네요
Mm. Makes me wish
we'd met sooner.
제가 FBI에서 한달 전쯤
안 좋은 일을 겪었거든요
I hit a rough patch here at the
bureau a month or so back.
안타깝네요,
잘 말 해드릴 수 있었는데
Oh, that's a shame. I could have
put in a good word for you.
누구한테요?
With who?
시장님 아니면 창문닦이요?
The mayor or the window washer?
누굴까요?
Who do you think?
제 생각에 당신의
진짜 기술은 허세예요
I think your real skill
is the art of the bluff,
연줄이 많다고 주장하지만
증명도 안 되잖아요
making claims you know full well
you can't back up.
네, 랜던 쉐퍼드인데
시장님과 통화하려고요
Yes, Landon Shepard
for the mayor.
네, 시장님
랜던 쉐퍼드예요
Hello, sir.
Landon Shepard.
그렇네요, 오랜만이네요
Indeed, it has been some time.
휴대 전화가 있단
사실은 알았네요
Well, we can confirm
she's got a cell.
그게 요원님의 작전이에요
That's Peter's play.
진짜 이름으로 등록됐다면
알았을 거예요
If it were registered under her
real name, we'd know about it.
영장을 받으려면
가명이나..
For a subpoena, we'd need
either her alias --
전화번호를 알면 되죠
Or her cell number.
시청의 전화 기록은
공공 기록이니까요
City Hall phone logs are public record.
Hmm.
좀 하시는데요
꽤 하세요
Not bad, Peter.
Not bad at all.
인사 전해드릴까요?
Shall I say hi?
고맙지만 됐습니다
No, thank you.
뭐 나왔나?
Anything?
Well, good news is,
좋은 소식은 전화 기록
9년치가 나왔다는 거죠
- we've got Shepard's phone
records dating back nine years. - Bad news?
나쁜 소식은?
전화 기록이 9년치나
나왔다는 거요
We've got Shepard's phone
records dating back nine years.
이름도 없고
모두 발신 번호예요
No names, all outgoing numbers.
수천 명은 될 거예요
I mean, there must be
thousands here.
참고로, 문신에 대한
얘긴 틀렸어요
And for the record,
she was wrong about my tattoo.
5년전이 아니라
4년전에 했어요
I got it four years ago,
not five.
그렇군요
Okay.
어제 연락한
번호에 집중해
Keep focusing
on calls made yesterday.
쉐퍼드와의 연관성을
알아낼 수 있다면..
If we can establish a link
between Shepard and --
- 잠깐만요
- 뭐가 나왔어?
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on.
You have something?
네, 이 번호요
Yeah, this number.
여기 또 있네요
There it is again.
여기 온통 익숙한
번호 투성이네요
Her number is
all over this thing.
이거..
Isn't th --
네
Yeah.
스털링보쉬는 몇 년동안
쉐퍼드를 고용해왔어요
Sterling Bosch has had Shepard
on retainer for years.
뭣 때문에요?
For what purposes?
함께 회수 작업을 했어요
We're in the business
of recovery.
회수할 물건에
장애물이 있으면
If someone stands between us
and something we want,
연줄을 이용해
협상하게 만들죠
she has the connections
to make them roll over,
문제 처리는
끝내주게 하거든요
and she is damn good
at cleaning up messes.
예를 들면?
Such as?
I may or may not have hired her
내가 이방카 트럼프의
환풍구에서
망가진 힐을 찾으려고
고용했을지도 모르고
to retrieve my broken heel
from Ivanka Trump's air vent.
묻지 마
Don't ask.
그럼 그 여자의
방식을 알겠네요
So, you're aware
of her methods.
아주 엄격한 룰이 있어요
She has very strict rules.
원하는 걸 말하면
완수하지만
You tell her what you need,
and she gets it done.
수단에 의의를 제기하거나
방법을 묻기만 해도
But if you question her means
or even ask what they are,
일을 거절해버려요
she will terminate the job.
결과를 어떻게 얻든
질문도 대답도 없군요
Don't ask how she gets her
results, and she won't tell you.
요원님, 쉐퍼드가 법을
준수하지 않지만
Peter, I know Shepard
isn't by the book,
딜랜시 같은
쓰레기를 도와
but I had no idea she'd work
for scum like Delancy,
연방 검사의 경력을
위협하는 건 몰랐어요
let alone threaten the career
of a federal prosecutor.
쉐퍼드가 법망 밖에서
일한단 걸 알았으니
We know Shepard works
below board.
스스로 범죄를 인정하게
만들면 어때요?
What if we can get her
to incriminate herself?
- 자백의 방법으로 쓰자고
- 네
Use it to leverage a confession.
Yeah.
브라이슨을 협박했다고
인정하게 하는 거야
Get her to admit that
she's extorting Bryson.
사라
Sara...
쉐퍼드가 스털링 보쉬에
얼마나 충실해요?
How loyal is Shepard
to Sterling Bosch?
꽤요, 왜요?
Very. Why?
자기 꾀에 자기가
넘어가게 할 방법을 알거든요
I think I know a way we can use
her own schemes against her.
도와줄래요?
You willing to help?
요원님을 위해서라면
For you...
뭘 해드릴까요?
What do I do?
쉐퍼드양
The Shepard hive.
전화줘서 고마워요
Thank you so much
for calling me back.
사라, 뭘 도와드릴까요?
Sara, what can I do for you?
맡길 일이 있어요
Well,
I have a job offer for you
좀 민감한 문제예요
that's a bit sensitive
in nature.
말씀만 하세요
Well, I'm here to help.
제 전 남자친구
스티브 타버나클이
My ex-boyfriend,
Steve Tabernackle,
저랑 어떤 남자의
낯뜨거운 사진을 갖고있는데
has some compromising photos
of me and another man
폭로하겠다고
협박하고 있어요
that he's threatening
to expose.
사진을 없애라고
설득할 수가 없어서
I can't convince him
to destroy them,
당신이 해줬으면 해요
so I was hoping
maybe you could.
타버나클이란 사람
꽤 불쾌한 것 같네요
Well, this Tabernackle sounds
very unpleasant.
불쾌하다는 정도론
표현이 안돼요
Oh, unpleasant doesn't even
begin to describe him.
금융 사기꾼에 절도범에
거짓말쟁이예요
He's a financial scammer,
an ex-con, a thief, a liar.
아시겠죠
You get the picture.
또 알아야 할 게 있나요?
Is there anything else
I should know?
네, 수요일엔 거의
Yes. Most wednesdays,
카날에서 전과자 여럿이
모여 판 큰 도박을 해요
he plays high-stakes Pai Gow on
Canal with a dozen ex-felons --
분명한 가석방
규율 위반이죠
clearly a violation
of his parole.
유용하게 쓰실지도
Maybe you can use that.
가석방범이 가장
싫어하는 건 감옥이죠
There's nothing a parolee hates
more than prison.
내일 이 시간쯤엔
So by this time tomorrow,
I just need assurances
다신 그 사진이 빛을
못 보게 확실히 처리해 주세요
that those pictures will never
see the light of day.
가장 좋아하는 고객을
위해선데요, 안심하세요
For one of my favorite clients,
consider it done.
정말 고마워요, 쉐퍼드
Thank you so much,
miss Shepard.
함께 일해서 즐거워요
It's a pleasure
doing business with you.
저를 협박하려는 걸
현행범으로 잡으면
So, once we catch her red-handed
trying to blackmail me...
딜랜시와 해결사의
자백으로 넘어가는 거지
We flip her on Delancy
and strong-arm a confession.
참고로 말씀드리면
For the record,
전 그런 낯뜨거운
사진이랑은 거리가 멀어요
I am very much not
the incriminating-photos type.
- 예전에..
- 닐, 단축 번호를 누르려다 그랬어
Well, there was --
Neal, I thought I was hitting speed dial.
- 그렇지
- 좋아
Right.
All right.
문제라면 스티브
타버나클의 이야기는
What matters is that
Steve Tabernackle's story
가석방 된 상태에서
멈춰있단 거야
is backstopped as a parolee.
쉐퍼드가 조사하겠지만
Shepard can dig,
닐을 FBI와
연관시키진 않을 거야
but she won't link Neal
to the FBI.
스티브 시절로 돌아간다니
Back in Steve's shoes.
사라, 스털링 보쉬의 해결사를
희생해줘서 고마워요
Sara, thank you for sacrificing
Sterling Bosch's Ms. Fix-it.
화이트 컬러에서의
평범한 하루죠
Just another day
at white collar.
아직 샘한테서 답장 없어?
Still no response from Sam?
어디든 계실 수 있죠
Could be anywhere.
다이애나가 D.C에 연락했어
Diana has a contact
in D.C.
그쪽에서 30년 전 경찰이었던
샘을 찾아보겠다고 했어
He offered to run a search
on a Sam in the Metro P.D.
30 years ago.
쉽지 않을 거야
Won't be easy without a --
Thanks, Peter, but when Sam's ready to talk,
감사하지만 샘이
준비되면 연락할 거예요
he knows how to find me.
- 무슨 일이냐?
- 무슨 소리예요?
What's going on?
What do you mean?
샘을 찾을 수 있는
방법을 제시했는데
I just offered you
a potential avenue to find Sam,
거절하다니
and you're telling me no.
엘렌이 죽은 시기가 이상해요
I've been thinking about
the timing of Ellen's death.
그게 왜?
What about it?
거의 30년 동안
증인 보호 아래 계셨는데
She's in WITSEC
for close to three decades,
FBI 보고서에 이름이
올라온지 몇 주만에..
and a few weeks after her name
pops up in some FBI report --
범인이 내부
사람일 거라는 거냐?
You think whoever killed her
had access?
배제할 순 없죠
We can't rule that out.
샘과 제가 함께 일하게 되면
If Sam and I end up
working together,
요원님도 함께이길 바래요
I want you involved --
you know that.
수사를 비공식화 한다면 말이지?
Only if I keep
the investigation off-book.
그런 말은 안했어요
I never said that.
- 할 필요도 없다
- 해주실 거예요?
You didn't have to.
And will you?
닐, 넌 답을 원하고
나도 돕고 싶어
Neal, I know you want answers,
and I want to help.
하지만 당장은 또다른
유보트에 뛰어 들 입장이 아니야
But right now,
I'm in no position
to be breaking into
another u-boat.
이번엔 잠수함이 아니잖아요
I doubt this involves a submarine.
Oh, no?
그래? 비행선이
있을지도 모르지
Maybe he's got a blimp.
좋아요, 알았어요
Okay. All right.
이해했어요
I get it.
쉐퍼드 사건에만 집중해
I need you focusing on Shepard.
법망을 벗어나도
아무 문제 없는 여자요
Someone who has no trouble working off-book.
연락해오면 알려줘
Let me know
if she contacts you.
그럴게요
I will.
잘 가세요, 요원님
Good night, Peter.
잘 가라, 닐
Good night, Neal.
도박 판을 휩쓸고 오셨나봐
Oh, I see you cleaned house
at Pai Gow.
넌 가짜 아기를 안고있네
I see you've got a fake baby.
우리의 신비한
샘에게 이끌 단서지
And a lead
on our mysterious Sam.
배릭의 제니스 렌트카에
회색 SUV가 나타났어
The gray S.U.V. pinged
at Zenith Rent-a-Car on Varick.
좋은 소식이네
근데 아기는 왜?
That's great news.
Still doesn't explain the baby.
바쏠로뮤가 그쪽 컴퓨터에
접속하게 도와줬어
Bartholomew helped me access
their mainframe.
컴퓨터 과학 학위라도 있어?
With his
computer-science degree?
얠 맥가이버 칼로 생각해
Think of him as a Swiss army knife.
Oh!
가끔 오줌을 싸지만
That occasionally wets himself.
SUV의 보수 기록이야
The S.U.V.'s
maintenance records.
사무엘 펠프스의 신용카드 번호
Credit-card number
for a Samuel Phelps.
모즈, 이거 대단한데
고마워
Moz, this is huge.
Thank you.
아저씨는 떠봤어?
Now, did you feel out the Suit?
- 응
- 그런데?
I did.
And?
지난 번 날 위해
비공식 수사를 했을때
And the last time he went off-book
for me, he almost lost his job.
해고되실 뻔 했잖아
더 알아낼 때까진
Until I know more,
요원님을 제외시키는 게
모두한테 안전해
it's safer for everyone
to keep Peter out of this.
여보세요?
Hello?
타버나클씨?
Mr. Tabernackle?
누구신가요?
Who is this?
만난 적은 없지만
공통 관심사는 많죠
We've never met, but we share
a number of interests --
사라 앨리스, 사진, 도박
Sara Ellis,
photography, gambling.
똑똑한 사람이라면
날 직접 만나겠죠
And if you're smart, you'll meet
me in person to discuss them.
내일 오전 10시 어때요?
How does 10:00 A.M. tomorrow
sound?
쉐퍼드가 테입에
확실하게 말해야 돼
I need you
to get Shepard on tape
explicitly
telling you to --
사진을 없애지 않으면
To destroy the photos
내 비리를 폭로하겠다고요
or she'll release the dirt
she's got on me.
협박을 피하는
방법은 좀 알죠
I know a thing or two
about avoiding blackmail.
증명하는 방법이겠지
You mean proving blackmail.
그렇게 말 안했나요?
That's not what I said?
네 질문이 답을 조종할 수
있단 걸 기억해
Remember, your questions
can steer her answers.
- 사기처럼요
- 증언처럼
Yeah, like a con.
Like testimony.
쉐퍼드가 나타났습니다
I've got eyes on Shepard.
시작하죠
Here we go.
그래
Yeah.
타버나클씨
Mr. Tabernackle.
뭘 원합니까?
What do you want?
사라의 사진을 갖고 있죠
없애길 바래요
You have photos of Sara Ellis
she'd like destroyed.
당신이 직접이요
I want you to make that happen.
안 없애면요?
And if I don't?
당신 친구에게 닥친 위험을
얼마나 감수 하는지 알아보죠
I find out what kind
of risk taker you are
when it comes to your friends.
무슨 속셈이야?
Where's she going with this?
어젯 밤
Last night,
스티브 타버나클의
수상한 친구가
one of Steve Tabernackle's
suspected associates
이걸 얻으려고
꽤 애썼더군요
went to great lengths
to obtain this.
저게 뭔지 알겠어?
Can you tell what it is?
영수증 종류 같은데요
Looks like an invoice
of some sort.
당신 물건이 아니에요
That doesn't belong to you.
이걸 얻으려고
15가지 법을 어긴
Nor does it belong
to the funny little bald man
who broke 15 laws
trying to obtain it,
웃기고 작은
대머리 것도 아니죠
그 중 3가지는
3 of which involved
가짜 고무 아기가
연관됐더군요
what I can only hope
was a fake rubber child.
젠장, 어제 닐을
미행한 게 아니라
Damn it. She wasn't following
Neal last night.
모지를 미행했어
She was following Mozzie.
왜 그런 이상한
방법까지 써서
Now, why would someone go
to such extraordinary lengths
지루한 서류를
얻으려했을까요?
for something so innocuous?
조사를 좀 해봤더니..
I did some digging.
It turns out --
사진을 없앨게요
I'll destroy the photos.
사진은 절대
빛을 못 볼겁니다
They'll never see
the light of day.
약속해요
You have my word.
무슨 짓을 한 거죠?
What did he just do?
전부 망쳐버렸어
He tanked it --
the whole damn thing.
쉐퍼드도 못 잡고
아무 소득 없이!
Shepard walks.
We got nothing!
정체성은 가족에게서 나오죠
Identity comes from family.
가족이 없는 사람은
우정을 소중히 생각하구요
And those without family
cherish their friendships.
당신이 택해요
Your choice.
이건 제가 보관하죠
Oh, I'll be holding on to this.
확실히 하기 위해서
Assurances and all.
반가웠어요
It's been a pleasure.
네가 망쳤어, 닐
You blew it, Neal.
재판에, 한 남자의
경력까지 네가 다 망쳤어
With a trial and a man's career
at stake, you blew it.
모지 이름이 FBI 파일에
오르면 모지가 알 거예요
If Mozzie's name ends up
in the FBI files, he's made.
공식 보고서에서
이름을 빼줄 수도 있었어
I could have excluded his name
from the official report.
- 알잖아
- 제가요?
You know that.
Do I?
그것도 공식적인
일은 아닌데요
That puts you off-book.
다 그것 때문이냐?
닐, 무슨 일이야?
Is that what this is about?
Neal, what's going on?
아까 그 종이는 뭐야?
What was on
that piece of paper?
모지가 알리고
싶어하지 않는 거예요
Something Mozzie
wouldn't want exposed.
- 그것만 말씀드릴 수 있어요
- 닐
That's all I can tell you.
Neal --
어쩔 수 없었어요
I didn't have a choice.
가봐라, 내일 보자
Get out of here.
I'll see you tomorrow.
당연히 아저씨가
수상하게 생각하셨겠지
Of course that made
the Suit suspicious!
내가 그 해결사한테
발각됐다니 말도 안돼
And the lady fixer made me.
I can't believe she made me.
네 잘못 아니야
실력 좋은 여자야
It's not your fault, Moz.
She's good.
그만큼 실력
좋은 사람은 없어
No one is that good.
왜 그런지 알아? 섬에서
너무 많은 시간을 보냈어
You know what this is?
Too much time on the island.
- 너무 약해졌어
- 말도 안돼
I've gone soft.
Don't be ridiculous, okay?
잘 봐
Watch.
한때는 이 기술로
사람도 죽였어
I once killed a man
with this trick.
그런 적 없잖아
You never killed a man
doing that.
할 수도 있었어, 한때는
I could have. Once.
됐어
That's it.
아루바에 가서 내 실력을
되찾아오겠어
I'm gonna go to Aruba
and get my edge back.
아루바에 가서 사과를
암살하기 전에
Before you go assassinating
apples in Aruba,
쉐퍼드를 막을 방법을
찾아주는 건 어때?
how about you help me find a way
to stop Shepard?
그건 아직 도울 수 있지
약점이 뭔데?
That I can still help you with.
What are her weaknesses?
완벽주의자란 거?
Well, she's a control freak.
고객이 자신의 방식에
의문을 제기하는 걸 싫어해
She hates it when her clients
question her methods.
그럼 장점은?
And her strengths?
연줄이 많고
Well-connected...
사람을 꿰뚫어보는거
Good at reading people.
스털링 보쉬처럼
오래된 고객이 많아
She has long-term clients
on the level of Sterling Bosch.
잘난 척은
Show-off.
여자의 장점을
역이용 할 방법은?
Any way to use her strengths
against her?
브라이슨의 사진을
없앨 방법을 찾았어요
I know how we can take Bryson's
extortion photos out of play.
말 해봐라
I'm all ears.
사라 앨리스랑
자보는 거 어떠세요?
How would you feel
about sleeping with Sara Ellis?
무슨 일인지 알아요?
Do you have any idea what this is about?
- 아뇨, 사모님은요?
- 전혀요
No. You?
No clue.
내가 왜 좋다고 했을까
정말 끔찍한 생각인데
Why did I agree to this?
This is a terrible idea.
더 좋은 생각이 있으시면
듣고 싶네요
Hey, if you have a better idea,
I would love to hear it.
좋아, 하지만 네가 말해
Fine.
But you should tell them.
네 잘난 생각이니까
It's your brilliant idea.
요원님 부인이잖아요
It's your wife.
네 전 여자친구잖냐
It's your ex-girlfriend.
그럼 제가 이야기를
주도하길 바라세요?
Oh, so you want me
to control the narrative?
- 같이 말 하자
- 좋아요
Let's tell them together.
Great.
- 좋아
- 하자구요
Great. All right.
Let's do it.
- 팀웍으로요
- 그래, 팀웍
Teamwork, right?
Yep. Teamwork.
- 우리 둘이요
- 그래
Okay? You and me.
Yep.
우선 이건 닐의
생각이었단 걸 말해둘게
I'd like to start by saying
this is Neal's idea.
요원님의 전폭적인
지원이 있었죠
That Peter supports 100%.
좋아, 누구든 그냥
말해줄래?
Okay. Can one of you
just please speak?
닐이 떠올린 생각인데..
Well,
it occurred to Neal --
- 저희가요
- 우리가..
Us.
Us --
쉐퍼드가 딜랜시를
고객 명단에서 제외시키면
That if Shepard were to drop
Delancy as a client,
딜랜시의 협박 계획은
물 건너 가는 거야
Delancy's extortion scheme
would go up in smoke.
쉐퍼드는 조쉬 사진을
계속 갖고 있겠지만
And Shepard would still have
the photos of Josh
사용할 동기가 없으니까
but would have no incentive
to use them.
그렇죠
Exactly.
그럼 어떻게 쉐퍼드가
딜랜시를 버리게 하죠?
So how do we get Shepard
to drop Delancy?
내가 아직도 딜랜시를
조사한다고 믿게 해서요
By convincing Delancy
that I am still a threat
to his freedom.
닐이 딜랜시와
위장 신분으로 일했었죠
I had Neal working undercover
on this one.
캐플린사에서 썼던
가명을 이용해서
Using my alias at Caplin,
딜랜시에게 요원님의
비리가 담긴 사진을 넘겨주면
I'll give Delancy dirt on Peter
that's so tempting,
쉐퍼드에게 그 사진을
쓰라고 할 거고
he'll insist Shepard uses it.
쉐퍼드는 거절할 거야
Shepard will refuse.
딜랜시는 자기
주장을 굽히지 않고
Delancy won't take no
for an answer.
자신에게 의문을 품은데
분개한 쉐퍼드와 다투고
She'll resent having her methods
questioned, so they'll argue.
쉐퍼드는 딜랜시를 고객
명단에서 빼, 그럼 해결이야
Shepard will drop Delancy
as a client, and poof.
브라이언을 협박하던
증거를 무효화시키는 거야
We've neutralized the extortion
threat against Bryson.
왜 쉐퍼드가 당신의
사진을 안 쓸거라고?
And why wouldn't she use
the dirt she has against you?
최고 고객에 대한 의리로
Out of her loyalty
to her best client.
최고 고객이 누군데?
Who's her best client?
보험 조사관이요
The insurance investigator
사모님 남편이랑 자는
who's sleeping with
your husband.
그럼, 그게..
Oh, uh --
it's --
아뇨, 안돼요
Oh! Oh, no. No, no.
사라는 이미 쉐퍼드한테
Sara already told Shepard
다른 남자와 찍은
낯뜨거운 사진이 있다고 했어요
that there are
compromising photos of her
with another man out there.
그 남자가 누군지는
말 안했잖아
You never mentioned
who that man was.
그러니까 그 사진을
진짜로 만들 수 있는 거지
Which gives us creative license
to make those photos real.
뭐?
What?
아니, 내 말은..
No, I mean --
진짜가 아니라..
진짜처럼 보이게 만든다고
Not real, but look real.
Real-looking.
그리고 당신도 있어도 돼
And you can
completely be there.
사진 속에?
In the photos?
아니, 아니
지켜봐도 된다고
No, no. I'm just saying
that you can watch.
정말 훈훈하겠네요
Oh, 'cause that
won't be awkward.
그게..
Well...Huh.
인정하긴 싫지만
효과는 있겠다
I hate to say it,
but I think it'll work.
네, 사진이 설득력만 있다면요
Yeah, as long as the photos
are...convincing.
좋아요
Okay.
설득력이 있단 얘긴..
By "convincing," you mean...
- 맨살이 좀 보여야지
- 적당히 탈의한 상태죠
I'm talking about showing a little skin.
A state of tasteful undress.
그걸 어디서 할 건데?
Where do you do this?
여보, 정말 여기
있어도 괜찮겠어?
Honey, you sure
you want to be here?
당신이 확신하는
일이라면
If you're sure
you're doing this,
난 괜찮아
I'm sure I want to be here.
사랑해
I love you.
닐, 어떻게 할까?
Neal, how do you want this?
이제 막 저녁을 먹고
It's like -- it's like you
just stumbled in from dinner.
좀 취한데다
You're a little drunk.
제일 중요한 건
But, you know,
most importantly...
욕망에 불타는 거야
You're burning with desire.
물어본 내 잘못이지
God, that's what I get
for asking.
어쩌죠?
즉흥적으로 해요?
What do we do?
Do we just wing this?
즉흥적으로!
Wing it!
그냥 되는대로 합시다
Yeah.
Yeah, let's just wing it.
- 그래요
- 즉흥적으로
Yeah.
Wing it.
- 좋아요
- 그래요
Okay.
All right.
좋아요
Okay.
이럴 거예요?
Seriously?
미안하지만
끼어들어야겠네
Okay, I'm sorry.
I-I've got to stop you.
졸업 무도회의 리무진
운전사가 된 기분이네
I feel like
a limo driver on prom night.
가려고?
You want to leave?
아니, 여보
재밌게 구경해야지
No. Honey, I want you
to get into it.
당신 격렬한 남자잖아, 섹시맨
Come on!
You're an intense, sexy man.
실력 발휘해봐, 어서
Show her what you got.
Come on.
- 알았어
- 좋아
All right.
Okay.
사라, 저기 조금만..
Yeah, Sara, just maybe --
조금만 긴장을 풀어봐
you know, maybe loosen it up
a little bit.
미안한데 뭐라고?
I'm sorry. What?
열정적으로 보여야 한다고
It needs to look passionate.
뭐, 이럼 좀 나아?
What, is this better?
Whoa.
그래, 그래/ 좋은데, 그치?/ 좋아요
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. That's good, right?
Okay.
- 그게..
- 됐어요
That's -- Oh --
There. All right.
진짜 이상하다
This is weird.
Uh...
여보, 왼손을 좀 아래로
내려봐, 더/ 더?
- Honey, put left hand down
a little further, further. - Lower?
그래, 그거야
Yeah, there you go.
- 사라, 다리로 잘 하는 거
- 닐, 알아서 할게!
Sara, do that thing with your leg.
Neal, I got it!
사라, 머리를 뒤로 젖혀봐요
Sara, maybe you could put
your head back.
- 뒤로요?
- 네, 좋아요
Back? Okay.
Yeah, there you go.
좋아요, 아주 좋은데요
There you go.
Wow. Okay, that's good.
섹시해요
That's hot.
로맨스 소설 커버감이네요
바로 그거예요
Romance-novel cover,
right there.
귀에 속삭여줘요
좋아하거든요
Whisper in his ear.
He likes that at home.
- 안녕, 피터
- 그래요, 좋아요
Oh, hi, Peter.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. That's good. Okay.
들어올려, 올려
Lift her up. Lift her.
Oh.
- 좋아, 뒤로 기대고
- 좋아요
- Yeah, there you go. Lean back.
- That's good.
조금만 더, 조금만 더
A little further.
A little further, yeah.
조심해요
Careful.
Oh!
Aah!
- Oh. Oh.
- Ohh!
좋아요
Okay.
된 것 같아요
I think we got it.
끝났어요
That's a wrap.
과학자 친구 왔구만
There's my scientist guy.
가택구금이 스타일까지
구속하진 못 했네요
Good to see house arrest hasn't
cramped your style, Delancy.
알콧
Alcott.
소문 들었네
Hey, I heard
through the grapevine
어제 밤 버크가
자넬 꽤 괴롭게 했다고
that, uh, Burke roughed you up
pretty good last night.
네, 그 망할 놈이
절 고발하려잖아요
Yeah, that son of a bitch
tried to turn me.
당신이 샘플을 오염시키도록
제가 눈감아줬다는 거예요
He says he knows I offered
to look the other way
so you could taint the samples.
사라진 벤젠을 찾고 있어요
He's after
that missing benzene.
젠장
Damn it.
네, 하지만 운 좋게도..
Yeah.
Well, lucky for us...
털어보니 먼지가 나더군요
He's no angel.
딱 걸렸죠
Busted.
좋아
I love it!
제가 도와드렸으니
Look, I helped you out.
당신도 절 도와주세요
I was hoping
you could help me, too.
이걸 처리해 줄 사람이 있지
I got somebody
that can take care of this.
정말요? 전 직장에서
짤리면 안 되거든요
Are you sure?
'Cause I cannot lose my job.
그래, 알아서 할게
No, no, no.
I got it.
- 자기?
- 응, 베이비
Honey?
Yeah, babe.
쉐퍼드가 왔어
들어오라고 할까?
Shepard's here.
You want me to let her in?
그래, 자기
Sure, hon.
호랑이도 제 말하면
온다더니, 여기 있어
Hey, speak of the devil,
stick around.
소개해 줄게
I'll introduce you to her.
그러고 싶지만
약속에 늦어서요
You know, I would, but I'm late
for an appointment.
- 다음에 뵙죠
- 좋아
I'll see you.
All right.
뒤에 있어요
He's in the back.
어젯 밤 음성 메일의
말투가 달갑지 않던데요
I didn't appreciate the tone
of your voicemail last night.
목표를 잘못 골랐다고
말했잖아
I told you,
you chose the wrong target.
내 덕분에 자유의 몸이
될 날도 머지 않았어요
You're days away from becoming
a free man, thanks to me.
버크가 다른 수를
쓰지 않는다면
Not if Burke's got
something to do with it.
버크는 완벽하다면서
I thought you said
he was untouchable.
어디서 났어요?
Where did you get these?
캐플린사에서
일하는 친구한테
Buddy at Caplin Environmental.
그 사진을 이용해
I want them in play.
- 이 사진들은 빛을 못 볼거예요
- 왜?
These photos will not see the light of day.
Why not?
- 그건 당신 알바 아니고요
- 이봐
That's none of your concern.
Hey.
당신 내 밑에서 일하잖아
You work for me.
버크한테 그만
캐고 다니라고 해
You tell Burke
to stop digging around,
아니면 이걸 공개한다고
or these will go public.
아무도 내 일에
이래라 저래라 못 해요
Nobody tells me
how to do my job.
네가 안 하면 내가 해
알았어?
You do it, or I will.
You hear me?
잘 있어요, 딜랜시
우린 끝이에요
Goodbye, Delancy.
We're done.
혼자 알아서 하세요
You're on your own.
뭐라고? 거래했잖아
Hey. What?
We had a deal, right?
내가 규칙을 만들고
I make the rules.
당신은 의의 제기
안하는 게 우리 거래였죠
You don't question them.
That was our deal.
- 이 사진은 가져가겠어요
- 안되지
And I'm taking these with me.
No, you're not.
나나 이 사진을 건드리면
If you touch me
or these photos,
버크가 확실히 벤젠
병을 찾도록 해주죠
I'll make sure that Burke
does find that vial.
요원님
Hey, Peter.
좋은 소식 전했어요?
You tell Josh the good news?
그래, 협박 사진은
이제 쓸모 없다고
Yeah, extortion photos
are off the table,
하지만 너무 늦었어
but it may be too little
too late.
무슨 일인데요?
Why? What happened?
피고측이 한 시간 전
변론을 마쳤어요
Defense rested an hour ago.
요원님의 증언을
제외시켰어요
They obliterated
Peter's testimony.
벤젠이 존재한
확실한 증거 없이는
Without hard proof
the benzene existed,
유죄 평결을
받을 방법이 없어요
there is no way I can get
a guilty verdict.
그 증거를 가져다 준다면요?
What if we can get you
that proof?
무슨 소리야?
What are you talking about?
쉐퍼드는 딜랜시의
벤젠을 없애지 않았어요
Shepard never destroyed
Delancy's vial of benzene.
그걸 딜랜시한테 계속
상기시키구요/ 왜요?
She's holding it over his head.
Why?
모지에 대한 증거
요원님과 사라의 사진
The evidence against Mozzie,
the pictures of you and Sara --
모든 걸 갖고 있구나
She holds on to everything.
그렇게 고객들을
주무르는 거야
It's the only way
she can control her client.
그러니까 자신을 위해
Which means the vial
is only good to her
딜랜시의 지문이 있는
벤젠 병을 잘 보존했죠
if it's well-preserved, complete
with Delancy's fingerprints.
재판이 3시에 재개 될때까지
제출해야 해요
It'd have to be submitted by the
time court resumes at 3:00.
두시간도 안남았네
That's less than two hours.
방법을 궁리해야겠어요
We need to figure out
how to find it.
How can you stall?
어떻게 시간을 끌거죠?
Well, the defense claims
that the vial never existed,
피고측에선 벤젠이
존재하지 않는다지만
존재를 아는 마지막
반대 증인을 부르면요?
but what if you called
one last rebuttal witness
who happens to know
that it did?
유일하게 병을 본 다른 사람
The only other person
who saw the vial.
닐 카프리, 증언대에 서 볼까요?
Neal Caffrey, how'd you like
to take the stand?
검사님
Hey.
3시에 증언할 거예요
You're on the stand
at 3:00.
피고측에선 당신 증언이
나한테 득될 거 없다고 생각해요
Defense assumes your testimony
will do me more harm than good.
낮은 기대치라 잘됐네요
Good. Low expectations.
하지만 벤젠을 못 찾으면
그 말이 맞을지 모르죠
Yeah, but if we don't find
that benzene, they may be right.
요원님한테 소식 없어요?
Any word from Peter?
통화 기록에
나온 모든 은행
Yeah, he's got all of
white collar flagging banks,
저장소, 창고에
전 직원을 동원했어요
storage facilities, and warehouses
from Shepard's call logs.
No leads yet,
아직 단서는 없지만
요원님이 몇 백개의
번호를 조사 중이에요
but there are still a few hundred
private numbers he's looking into.
몇 백개요?
A few hundred?
추가 일손을
데려왔거든요
Well, we brought in
some extra help.
리모 서비스
Limo service, limo service,
검사관, 검사관
줄리아니
comptroller,
comptroller, Giuliani.
그런데 줄리아니는 이제
제 전화를 받지 않아요
By the way, Giuliani never
returns my phone calls anymore.
모모푸고, 모모푸고
Momofuku, Momofuku.
넌 대체 어느 별에서 왔냐?
Where did you come from?
45년전에 이니그마가 패러독스에게
특별한 포옹을 해준 곳이요
45 years ago, an enigma gave
a paradox a very special hug.
잠깐만요
Oh. Wait a minute.
쉐퍼드가 매달 2일에
같은 번호로 전화를 했어요
Shepard calls the same number
on the second of every month.
어디야?
What is it?
미드타운의 창고시설이요
Storage facility in midtown.
- 고객만 이용하는 비공개 시설이에요
- 너도 고객이야?
Unpublished, for clients only.
You're a client?
고객만 이용하는
비공개 시설이요
Unpublished, for clients only.
벤젠을 찾을 수
있을지도 모르겠는데
I think we may have found
our benzene.
닐이 증언대에 서려면
한시간도 안 남았어
Neal takes the stand
in less than an hour.
영장 받을 시간이 없어
Not enough time for a warrant.
아니면 쉐퍼드가 직접 창고에서
병을 꺼내오게 하는 거지
Although, if we could
somehow convince Shepard
to get the vial
out of storage...
현행범으로 체포한다
You can catch her
red-handed.
그 생각 맘에 드는데요
Suit, I like the way
you're thinking.
지난 밤엔 뭘 하다
쉐퍼드한테 들킨 거야?
What did she catch you doing
the other night?
무관한 질문이에요
Irrelevant.
빚을 갚을 시간인거죠
도움을 드려요, 말아요?
This is about payback, right?
Do you want my help or not?
도와줘
I do.
하지만 불법은 안돼
법의 테두리 안에서
But nothing illegal,
and it stays aboveboard.
아저씨만 법의
테두리를 지키면요?
What if I could arrange
for you to be aboveboard?
발뺌의 여지를 남긴다?
Plausible deniability?
전엔 제대로 먹혔어요
It's worked for us before.
어서 하자
Let's do it.
다 왔다
다음은?
We're here.
What's next?
좋아요
Okay.
여기요
Here.
1983년 3월경 파리의
오디오 일기예요
My Parisian audio diary,
circa march 1983.
볼륨 최대로
Max volume.
서쪽을 보세요
Okay, uh, face west.
아니..동쪽이요
No, I-I mean east.
낯선자가 내 아파트에
다시 나타났다
Strangers turned up
in my apartment again.
이젠 거의 매일 밤 나타난다
It happens most nights now.
처음엔 내가 문을 열었으니
이해할 수 있었지만
The first time, I opened the door,
so I can understand.
이젠 강제로 문을
열고 들어온다
But now they just push
past the gate.
쉐퍼드양, 레일린 창고의
레니라고 합니다
Miss Shepard.
Lenny from Raylan.
창고에 파이프가 터졌어요
We're dealing with kind of a
pipe-burst situation over here,
망가지기 전에 물건을
가져가시라고 전화드렸어요
and we're consulting our clients
to remove their belongings
before they get damaged.
난 항상 레드 와인과
화이트 와인을 갖고 있어야 했지만
I must always have
a bottle of red
and a bottle of white on hand,
때로 그들은 카드 게임을 원한다
and sometimes
they want a card game.
저기, 제프리..안돼!
Look, it's -- Oh!
Jeffrey, no! No! Oh, no!
당신, 하고 말했다
스페인 사람 옆집에 살죠
"You," I say, "you're next door
to the Spanish.
"뉴저지에서 불어를 썼다면
"If New Jersey spoke French,
몇 마디는 알아들었을텐데
perhaps then
I would have picked some up."
나머지 듣고 싶으시면
언제든 빌려드릴게요
You can borrow it anytime
to hear the rest.
다음은 뭐냐?
What's next?
제리의 가게에 가서
엠파나다를 주문하세요
Okay, I need you to go down
to loco Jerry's.
Order an empanada --
sin queso --
그리고 차에서 기다리세요
then wait in the car.
먹진 말아요
Do not eat it.
무슨 소리를 듣거나 봐도
And no matter
what you see or hear,
쉐퍼드가 들어갈때까지
절대 차에서 나오지 마세요
do not exit the vehicle until
Shepard is inside that building.
아님 그냥 여기서
작업을 구경하시든가
Or you can just stay here
and watch us work.
엠파나다를 사마
I'll get the empanada.
비공개로 재판이
진행됩니다, 브라이슨 검사
We've closed the court,
Mr. Bryson.
증인을 부를 준비가 되었나요?
Are you or are you not prepared
to call your witness?
재판장님, 검사측에선
Your honor, the prosecution
would like to call
닐 카프리를
증인으로 부르겠습니다
Mr. Neal Caffrey
to the stand.
피고가 존재를 부인하는
벤젤 병의 목격자입니다
He's an eyewitness
to the benzene vial
the defense claims
never existed.
뭐야?
What?
어서, 모지
Come on, Mozzie.
뭘 하고 있든 서둘러
Whatever you're up to...
존스, 다이애나
움직일 준비해
Jones, Diana,
get ready to move.
기록을 위해 풀 네임을
말씀해주시겠습니까
Would you state your full name
and title for the court?
닐 조지 카프리입니다
협력 증인이며
Neal George Caffrey,
cooperating witness
FBI에서 자문을 담당합니다
and confidential informant
for the FBI.
FBI라고?
FBI?
카프리씨, 위장 수사를
하게 된 이유는요?
Mr. Caffrey,
why were you sent undercover?
좀 긴 얘긴데요
Well, it's a bit
of a long story.
시간은 많습니다
We have time.
여기서 뭐해요, 쉐퍼드?
What you doing, Shepard?
버크 요원님
Agent Burke.
사유 재산을 침수시킬
사람으론 안 봤는데
Didn't peg you as the type
to flood private property,
그래도 절대 아내 몰래
바람 안 피는건 알아요
though I do know that you'd
never cheat on your wife.
적정 선을 정하는
모습이 꽤 흥미롭네요
It's so interesting to see where
one chooses to draw the line.
그 사진이 연출된 걸 알았다면
If you knew those photos
were staged,
왜 속는 척했어요?
why'd you play along?
딜랜시는 괴팍한 멍청이고
Because Delancy's
a temperamental idiot
사라 앨리스를
존중하니까요
and I respect Sara Ellis.
당신을 감옥에
넣으려고 했는데요
She wants you behind bars.
아뇨, 아니에요
No. She doesn't.
하지만 당신이 편을
택하게 만들었요
But you made her choose a side.
사라가 아니라
당신 탓이죠
I blame you for that, not her.
복수의 시간이다
Time for payback.
뚫어, 아가야, 뚫어
Drill, baby, drill.
병은 트렁크에 있어요
Vial's in the trunk.
체포하시죠, 요원님
Cuff me, agent.
기꺼이요
With pleasure.
Mm-hmm.
궁금하네요
I'm curious.
법 준수를 택한 사람이
이 상황은 어떻게 설명할 거죠?
How does a man who's chosen
to uphold the law explain this?
요원님, 무슨 일이에요?
Hey.
What happened here?
말하자면 길어
Long story.
감시해, 난
트렁크를 살펴볼게
Watch her.
I'm gonna check the trunk.
마법이 깨졌나보군요
Looks like
your spell's been broken.
거래를 해요
Make you a deal.
병을 증거물로
보관한 걸 확인해 주면
Verify the chain of custody
on that vial,
and maybe we'll go
a little easier on you.
좀 봐줄지도 모르죠
그거야 가능하죠
I can work with that.
괜찮으세요, 요원님?
Everything okay, Peter?
그래, 필요한 건 다 얻었어
Yeah.
We all got what we needed.
이걸 법원에 가져가야겠어
I got to get this
to the courthouse.
바티, 우리 실력을
되찾은 것 같다
Well, Barty, looks like
we got our edge back.
줄리아니가 내 전화를
받을 이유가 있는 거지
And Giuliani has a reason
to return my calls.
카프리씨, 피고가 보여준 병은..
Mr. Caffrey, the vial
the defendant showed you --
어느 정도 크기였나요
what size would you say it was?
이의있습니다
Objection!
재판장님, 이미 했던 질문입니다
Your honor, asked and answered.
인정합니다, 검사측
논지는 충분히 알아들었으니
Sustained. Mr. Bryson, you've covered
the ground you need to cover.
피고측이 반대 심문을
하도록 하거나
Either allow the defense to
cross-examine the witness or --
어딜 가는 겁니까?
Hey! Where do you
think you're going?!
카프리씨, 이게
작년 11월 1일에
Mr. Caffrey, is this the vial
Victor Delancy showed you
빅터 딜랜시가
보여준 병입니까?
on November 1st of last year?
그런 것 같군요
I believe it is.
당신은 2주동안 캐플린사에서
성공한 생화학 분석가로 일했죠
Mr. Caffrey, for two weeks you worked
as a highly successful
senior biochemical analyst
at Caplin Environmental.
이의있습니다
Objection.
가짜 과학자였다는 게
How does being a fake scientist
어떻게 벤젠을 검사할
자격이 된다는 겁니까?
qualify this man
to identify benzene?
저도 답변을 듣고 싶군요
I'd very much like an answer
to that myself.
재판장님, 저는 채권 위조로
유죄 판결을 받았습니다
Your honor, I was
convicted of bond forgery.
위조는 예술만큼이나
과학적입니다
Forgery is as much science
as it is art.
정부에선 당신을
위조 전문가로 여기나요?
And does the government consider
you an expert in forgery?
모든 타입의 위조요
Of all types --
예술품, 채권, 수표
art, bonds, checks.
수표를 위조하는
과정을 설명해주시겠습니까?
Would you please explain to
the court what check washing is?
수표의 세탁은
Check washing is the process
수표의 잉크를
용해시키는 겁니다
of dissolving the ink
from a check,
얼마든 금액을
다시 적을 수 있죠
allowing it to be rewritten
for any amount.
어떻게 그렇게 됩니까?
And how is that accomplished?
보통은 벤젠에 담그죠
Well, typically, the check
is soaked in benzene.
그럼 벤젠이 독성
오염원일 뿐 아니라
So, not only is benzene
a toxic pollutant,
범죄자가 수표의 잉크를
지우는 약품이란 거군요
it's also a chemical
criminals use
to remove ink
from a personal check?
그렇습니다
That's correct.
카프리씨, 사기꾼이자
거짓말쟁이로 유명한 분인데
Mr. Caffrey, when you're known
in some circles
as a con man and a liar,
당신 말을 왜 믿어야하죠?
why should we believe a word
of any of this?
믿지 마세요
사람은 거짓말을 하니까요
Oh, you shouldn't.
People lie.
하지만 과학은 못 하죠
But science doesn't.
과학자도 아니잖아요
He's not a scientist.
여러분 증거물 64a를
제시하겠습니다
Ladies and gentlemen,
I present to you exhibit 64a.
버크 요원과
카프리씨가 확인하고
As confirmed by agent Burke,
Mr. Caffrey,
and verified through
the chain of custody,
증거물 보존이 확인되었으니
이 병은 작년 11월 6일에
사라진 병입니다
we now know this is the vial
removed from Delancy's office
November 6th of last year.
과학으로 이 물질이
벤젠이란 걸 증명하실 수 있나요?
Can you please demonstrate
for the court
how science can prove
this vial contains benzene?
물론이죠
Absolutely.
재판장님, 펜 좀 빌려주십시오
Uh, your honor,
I'll need your pen, please.
그리고 피고측의 물도요
And the defendant's glass
of water.
감사합니다
Thank you, sir.
Ahh. Wow.
목이 탔나봐요
I guess I was thirsty.
보시는 바와 같이 지금
조지 알콧에게 수표를 씁니다
Let the record show
that I am writing a check
to George Alcott --
great guy, sharp as a tack --
멋지고 똑똑한 친구죠
100달러 짜리입니다
in the amount of $100.
이 병의 액체가 벤젠이라면
Now, if the liquid in this vial
is benzene,
이 수표의 잉크는 5초만
담궈도 완전히 사라집니다
the ink from this check
will disappear completely
within five seconds of contact.
유독 가스는 죄송합니다
Pardon the fumes.
좋아요
All right.
보세요
Here we go.
4,3,2
Four, three, two...
어림잡아 5초였군요
Five seconds.
Give or take, apparently.
보시는 바와 같이
Let the record show,
액체에 잠긴 부분의
잉크는 완전히 사라졌습니다
where the check was submerged,
the ink has vanished completely.
사실 중심 전략으로
진행했습니다
Ours is
a fact-driven process.
그 사실을 수집한 분들께
감사하고 싶네요
You know, I'd like to thank
those who gathered those facts,
사실에 무게를 두고 바른
결정을 내린 배심원들께도요
as well as the jury
for weighing them
and arriving
at the right conclusion.
제 과학 수업이 배심원에게
긍정적 효과를 끼치다니 기쁘네요
Glad to see my science lesson
had a positive effect
on the jury.
브라이언 말론 우즈
재판도 다가온다는데
Oh, uh, Bryson mentioned
the woods trial is coming up.
너랑 같이 하고 싶대
He'd love to have you.
패스할래요
I think I'll pass.
증언은 재밌었지만
Testifying's fun,
생각 만큼의
사기는 아니더라구요
but it's not as much of a con
as I thought.
사실만 말하는 건
적성에 안 맞아?
Telling the whole truth
isn't your cup of tea?
놀라운데
I'm shocked.
전 볼 일이 있어서
괜찮으시면..
Listen, I got an errand to run.
Do you mind if I --
- 가봐, 내일 보자
- 네
Go. I'll see you tomorrow.
See ya.
당신의 C.I군요
Your C.I.
눈치 챘어야 했는데
I should have known.
쉐퍼드, 어떻게 나온 거예요?
Shepard, how the hell
did you get out?
출두 서약서를
제출하고 풀려났죠
The judge released me
on my own recognizance.
바른 사람한텐
잡힐 수도 있더군요
It's amazing what knowing
the right people can get you.
그렇죠
Yes, it is.
그리고 게임 정말
잘 치르셨어요
Oh, and my compliments
on a game well played.
- 협박도 게임이었어요?
- 그럼요
Extortion's a game to you?
Of course.
주변 사람들이
법을 어기는 동안
Oh, and your strategy --
staying above the law
법의 테두리 안에
머무는 당신 전략
while the people around you
break it --
대단해요
it's genius.
론 내키지 않는 일도 해야죠
Well, sometimes we have to do
things we don't like
아끼는 이들을
보호하려면요
to protect the people
we care about.
브라이슨 얘긴가요
아님 카프리?
Are you talking about Bryson
or your boy Caffrey?
믿을 수 없는 사람이죠
He's slippery,
옳고 그름의 경계
또한 그렇구요
and so is the line
between right and wrong.
그 경계를 넘어
카프리를 따라갈 땐
And when you follow him
across it,
모든 걸 잃게 될 거예요
it will cost you everything.
내가 틀렸길 바래요
I hope I'm wrong.
하지만 아니라면
전화줘요
But if I'm not...
Call me.
기꺼이 도울게요
I'm here to help.
저 없이 엘렌의 증거를
찾을 수 있다 생각하시면
If you think you can find
Ellen's evidence without me...
틀리셨어요
You're wrong.
왜 그렇지?
Why is that?
그렇게 꼭꼭 숨어 계셨어도
'Cause I'm standing here
talking to a man
이렇게 찾아냈으니까요
who doesn't want to be found.
전 누구보다 놈들을
잡고 싶어요
Sam, no one wants these guys
taken down more than me.
지난 십년동안 진실에서
도망치며 살았어요
I spent the last decade of
my life hiding from the truth.
이제 직면할 준비가 됐어요
I'm finally ready to face it,
제가 도움이 안된다고
돌려보내시면 절대 안돼요
and I'll be damned
if I'm turning back now
because you think
I can't help you.
FBI 없이?
No FBI?
FBI 없이요
No FBI.
네 아버지랑 난 종종
다트를 하곤 했다
Your father and I used to
play darts once in a while.
지는 걸 죽도록 싫어했지
He hated losing with a passion.
그 아비에 그 아들이구나
Like father, like son.
다트라고요?
Darts, huh?
그럼 이제 어쩌죠?
So what now?
계속 연락하고..
We stay in touch...
정보를 나누고..
We share information...
무슨 수를 써서든
놈들을 잡는 거지
And we do whatever it takes
to bring them down.
닐, 뭘 하는 거냐
Neal, what are you doing?